<!DOCTYPE frameset SYSTEM "frameset.dtd">
<frameset>
    <predicate lemma="arise">
        
        
        <roleset framnet="Coming_to_be" id="arise.01" name="come into existence (from)" vncls="48.1.1">
            <roles>
                <role descr="thing (state) arising" f="" n="1">
                    
                    <vnrole vncls="48.1.1" vntheta="theme"/>
                </role>
                
                <role descr="source (from or in or of)" f="" n="2">
                    
                    <vnrole vncls="48.1.1" vntheta="location"/>
                </role>
                
                <note/>
            </roles>
            
            <example name="unaccusative" src="" type="">
                <text>Mr. Guber and Mr. Peters claim they have an oral agreement with
                    Warner executives that allows them to terminate their contract
                    should the opportunity to run a major studio arise.
                </text>
                <arg f="mod" n="m">should</arg>
                <arg f="" n="1">the opportunity  to run a major studio</arg>
                <rel f="">arise</rel>
                <note/>
            </example>
            
            <example name="odd kind of source" src="" type="">
                <text>The current opportunities arise because the process for executing
                    a buy or sell order in the actual stocks that make up the S&amp;P
                    500 is more cumbersome than transacting in the futures market.
                </text>
                <arg f="" n="1">The current opportunities</arg>
                <rel f="">arise</rel>
                <arg f="" n="2">because the process for executing a buy or         sell order in the actual stocks that make up the S&amp;P 500         is more cumbersome than transacting in the futures         market</arg> 
                <note/>
            </example>
            
            <example name="split construction" src="" type="">
                <text>Speculation has also arisen that the UAL executive most closely
                    identified  with the failure to gain bank financing, chief
                    financial officer John Pope, may come under pressure to resign.
                </text>
                <arg f="" n="1">[ Speculation ] [ that the UAL executive most         closely identified with the failure to gain bank financing,         chief financial officer John Pope, may come under pressure  to         resign]</arg> 
                <arg f="dis" n="m">also</arg>
                <rel f="">arisen</rel>
                <note>Note that in this case you MUST include the complementizer; the
                    sentence is ungrammatical without it.
                </note>
            </example>
            
            
            
            <example name="more normal source" src="" type="">
                <text>John's loneliness arises from his poor personal hygiene.</text>
                <arg f="" n="1">John's loneliness</arg>
                <rel f="">arises</rel>
                <arg f="from" n="2">his poor personal hygiene</arg>
                <note/>
            </example>
            
            
            
            <note>Member of Vncls appear-48.1.1. Comparison to 'come about'.</note>
        </roleset>
        <note>Frames file for 'arise' based on sentences in financial subcorpus.</note>
    </predicate>
    <note/>
</frameset>
