<!DOCTYPE frameset SYSTEM "frameset.dtd">
<frameset>
  <predicate lemma="overpresent">
    <roleset id="overpresent.01" name="overrepresent; present (statistically) more often than is true or fair">
      <aliases>
        <alias framenet="" pos="v" verbnet="">overpresent</alias>
      </aliases>
      <note>OVERPRESENT-V NOTES: Added by Julia based on BOLT. No VNcls. This sense corresponds to present.01, not present.102, the clinical sense. A different sense should be made for that if it comes up. (from overpresent.01-v)</note>
      <roles>
        <role descr="agent of (re)presentation" f="PAG" n="0"/>
        <role descr="entity (re)presented" f="ppt" n="1"/>
      </roles>
      <example name="arg 1" src="BOLT" type="">
        <inflection aspect="ns" form="ns" person="ns" tense="ns" voice="passive"/>
        <text>This relentless obsession with white privelege and equal opportunities is absurd in the Britain of 2011 ; most of the richest men in the country are Indian , Jew or Russian and Asians-1 are statistically overpresented *T*-1 in higher professional fields , exam results etc yet escape all that inverted class snobbery</text>
        <arg f="mnr" n="m">statistically</arg>
        <rel f="">overpresented</rel>
        <arg f="" n="1">*T*-1</arg>
        <arg f="loc" n="m">in higher professional fields, exam results etc</arg>
      </example>
      <example name="Arg 1, PRD and ADV" src="internet" type="">
        <inflection aspect="ns" form="ns" person="ns" tense="ns" voice="ns"/>
        <text>The authors found that persons of color were heavily presented in stories about crime, and within those stories were more likely to be presented as perpetrators of crime than as persons reacting to or suffering from it. An analysis using recent homicide rates in Philadelphia and a rational model of expected victimization indicated that contrary to a realistic conflict explanation, [White actors]-1 were overpresented *T*-1 as victims of violence compared to their roles as perpetrators, and persons of color were overpresented as perpetrators of violence against White actors.</text>
        <rel f="">overpresented</rel>
        <arg f="" n="1">*T*-1</arg>
        <arg f="prd" n="m">as victims of violence</arg>
        <arg f="adv" n="m">compared to their roles as perpetrators</arg>
      </example>
    </roleset>
  </predicate>
</frameset>
