<!DOCTYPE frameset SYSTEM "frameset.dtd">
<frameset>
  <predicate lemma="premiere">
    <roleset id="premiere.01" name="give/have first performance">
      <aliases>
        <alias framenet="" pos="v" verbnet="">premiere</alias>
        <alias framenet="" pos="n" verbnet="">premiere</alias>
      </aliases>
      <note>PREMIERE-V NOTES: Quoth the American Heritage Dictionary:"premiere as a verb isunacceptable to a large majority of the Usage Panel, despite its wideusage in the world of entertainment." (from premiere.01-v)</note>
      <note>PREMIERE-N NOTES: (from premiere.01-n)</note>
      <roles>
        <role descr="causal agent" f="PAG" n="0"/>
        <role descr="thing premiering" f="PPT" n="1"/>
      </roles>
      <example name="premiere-v: ergative" src="" type="">
        <inflection aspect="ns" form="full" person="ns" tense="future" voice="active"/>
        <text>The operator of cable-television networks said the new Turner Pictures unit will produce movies that [*T*-1] will premiere on Turner Broadcasting 's Turner Network Television channel, or TNT, and then will be released internationally in movie theaters.</text>
        <arg f="" n="1">[*T*-1]</arg>
        <arg f="RCL" n="M">that -&gt; movies</arg>
        <arg f="MOD" n="M">will</arg>
        <rel f="">premiere</rel>
        <arg f="LOC" n="M">on Turner Broadcasting's Turner Network Television channel, or TNT,</arg>
      </example>
      <example name="premiere-v: agentive" src="" type="">
        <inflection aspect="ns" form="full" person="ns" tense="future" voice="active"/>
        <text>Tonight, to kick off the effort, CNN will premiere its first prime-time newscast in years, an hourlong show at 6 p.m. Eastern time to air head-to-head against the network newscasts.</text>
        <arg f="TMP" n="M">Tonight</arg>
        <arg f="PNC" n="M">to kick off the effort</arg>
        <arg f="" n="0">CNN</arg>
        <arg f="MOD" n="M">will</arg>
        <rel f="">premiere</rel>
        <arg f="" n="1">its first prime-time newscast in years, an hourlong show at 6 p.m. Eastern time to air head-to-head against the network newscasts</arg>
      </example>
      <example name="premiere-n" src="" type="">
        <text> Their premiere of Garrett-Moulton’s “A Show of Hands,” described by the SF Chronicle as “the greatest dance bargain offered in this town since the San Francisco Ballet performed in Stern Grove last summer,” took place in October 2013.</text>
        <arg f="" n="0">their</arg>
        <rel f="">premiere</rel>
        <arg f="" n="1">of Garrett-Moulton’s “A Show of Hands,” described by the SF Chronicle as “the greatest dance bargain offered in this town since the San Francisco Ballet performed in Stern Grove last summer,”</arg>
      </example>
    </roleset>
  </predicate>
</frameset>
